# **Andrew Hercules**

Developer. Designer. Digital Strategist.

Phone: +44 7511 311 454 | Email: andrewhercules@gmail.com | Web: andrewhercules.com

# PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a London-based web developer, user experience (UX) researcher and designer, and digital strategist. With a diverse and transferable skillset and a range of industry experience, I support and guide organisations that want to transform their operations with technology. Applying a user-centered, co-operative design approach, I research, design, and build solutions that meet the needs of users while streamlining and improving existing organisational practices.

#### **SKILLS**

Web Development JavaScript (Angular, React, jQuery); Ruby (Rails, Sinatra); HTML5; CSS3

**User Experience (UX)** user research methodologies; user journeys and stories; user personas; storyboarding; wireframing; prototyping; user testing; usability testing

**Digital Strategy** content development; information architecture; competitor analysis; web/graphic design; search engine optimisation (SEO); web analytics; accessibility standards; communications and public relations; digital marketing; e-commerce; m-commerce

**Tools** MS Office; Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator); prototyping software (Axure, Sketch, Keynote); text editors/IDEs (Atom, Visual Studio Code, Sublime, Xcode)

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Developer and UX Researcher/Designer**

University of London Computer Centre

October 2015 – present

- Build and customise institutional repositories for academic and research institutions using opensource software, plugins, and libraries
- Meet with new and existing customers to understand user needs and build requirements documents and user stories
- Complete user research projects for a range of educational and research clients, including:
  - 1. The UK's leading provider of on-campus residential and academic infrastructure
  - 2. Bloom, the University of London's bespoke Virtual Learning Environment
  - 3. The Royal Veterinary College, the UK's top-ranked veterinary school
- Support the marketing team's social media, content, and inbound marketing campaigns by repurposing research outputs for white papers and guest blogs
- Hire, train, and mentor new staff, including the team's Graduate Designer and Graduate Developer and work placement students
- Complete other special projects as needed (e.g. board presentations, project estimations, etc.)

# Front-End Developer and UX/UI Consultant

Deloitte Digital

June 2015 - October 2015

- Project Aztec (one of Europe's largest insurance companies):
  - Collaborated with colleagues across multiple business units to build a proof of concept application that provided existing insurance customers with online robo-advice
  - Transformed static mockups and user stories into an interactive single page application using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript libraries
- Project IM Mobile TfL (Transport for London):
  - Coordinated on-site user testing sessions and feedback sessions to promote a culture of transparency, accountability, and user-centred design
  - Wrote recommendation reports based on research findings and created design patterns that were used for subsequent mobile app development projects
  - o Developed static mockups with Photoshop and Illustrator

# **Freelance Digital Consultant**

June 2014 – April 2015

Self-Employed / Freelance

- Provided branding, photography, and staffing consultancy services to Minds Matter Magazine, the first student-led magazine about mental health at the University of Toronto Scarborough
- Worked with the Department of Arts, Culture and Media to develop short- and medium-term marketing strategies and succession planning documents
- Collaborated with a start-up law firm in Toronto to develop content marketing strategies

# **Communications Coordinator and Front-End Developer**

October 2011 – September 2014

University of Toronto – Department of Arts, Culture and Media

- Created a range of print and electronic promotional materials and campaigns and ensured design work was in line with university and departmental trademark and branding protocols
- Acted as the lead design consultant and collaborated with key stakeholders to redevelop the departmental website and transition from basic HTML/CSS to the Drupal CMS framework
- Developed email newsletters with MailChimp and HTML/CSS and implemented content and layout strategies, which led to consistent open rates above 25% (industry average - 17.1%)
- Produced annual reports and funding applications, which resulted in \$45,000 CAD in funding over three years (2012-2014) to support and enhance departmental events and programming
- Hired and supervised 3-6 casual staff members working in design/technical/website positions

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Ongoing Training & Development**

Ruby on Rails; Axure Prototyping; UX Research Methods; Google Analytics; Accessibility Standards

## Master of Arts, Journalism & Media

August 2008 – May 2010

Aarhus University, University of Amsterdam, City University London

## **Bachelor of Arts, Political Science**

September 2004 – June 2008

York University